<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<vxml version="2.1">
  <form>
    <field name="cotton" type="digits">
      <prompt>
      What information do you want to check?
      For Cotton Plant Information, press one.
      For how to Grow Cotton, press two.
      For cotton growing conditions, press three.
      For cotton seeding, seeding rate and number of plants, press four.
      For Fertilization Requirements for Cotton Plants, press five.
      For Cotton Water Requirements, press six.
      For Cotton Harvest and Yield, press seven.
      For Weed Control in Cotton, press eight.
      If you want to end this cotton information, press zero.
      </prompt>
      <filled>
         <if cond="actions == '0'">
          <prompt>Ok. Now you can end this cotton information.</prompt>
          <goto next= "goodbye.xml"/>
        <elseif cond="cotton == '1'">
          <prompt>
            The cotton plant is a shrub that is widely cultivated in more than 90 countries for the production of fiber 
            and to a lesser extent, seeds. 
            About 2.5% of the world's arable land is used for cotton cultivation. 
            It is an angiosperm, dicotyledonous plant belonging to the Mallowaceae family. 
            Cotton is native to Asia and Africa. 
            Like tomatoes, peppers and other plants, cotton is a perennial in its native place, but today we cultivate it as an annual. 
            This means we plant the seeds in the spring and harvest the cotton in the fall. 
            Afterwards plow and destroy the plants, and reseed the following spring in the clearing.
            Cotton is grown in regions with warmer climates. 
            China, the United States, Uzbekistan, Brazil and Turkey are the world's leading cotton producers. 
            In the United States, cotton is grown commercially mainly in the southern states 
            such as Texas, California, Georgia, Arkansas, Oklahoma and so on.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "cotton.xml"/>
        <elseif cond="cotton == '2'" />
          <prompt>
          Cotton Like tomatoes, peppers, and other plants, cotton plants are perennial in nature. 
            However, since we want a fairly even and satisfying yield each year, it is grown as an annual. 
            Unfortunately, cotton can only be grown commercially in areas with specific growing conditions. 
            Buying fresh and carefully selected cotton seeds is the first step to getting the desired yield. 
            The second step is to field prepare to welcome the seeds and facilitate their germination. 
            Sowing of cotton seeds takes place in spring. 
            Fertilization, irrigation and pest control are the keys to good yields and are where most of the cost comes from. 
            Unfortunately, cotton plants are very sensitive to various weeds. 
            They compete with cotton plants for water, nutrients and sunlight. 
            Cotton weed control techniques and management vary widely from country to country.
            Cotton is harvested in the fall. 
            Immediately after harvesting, we destroy the plants so that they can be sown again in the open field the following spring.
            In most parts of the United States, planting occurs March-May and harvest occurs August to October. 
            In Australia, the sowing time is September-November and the harvest time is March-May.  
         </prompt>
          <goto next= "cotton.xml"/>
        <elseif cond="cotton == '3'" />
          <prompt>
            Cotton is a plant that requires long frost-free periods, lots of heat, and full sun. 
            It likes warm and humid climates. 
            Cotton seeds will have poor germination rates if the soil temperature is below 60°F (15°C). 
            During active growth, the ideal air temperature is 70-100°F (21-37°C). 
            Temperatures well above 100°F are not advisable. 
            However, the average cotton plant can survive short-term temperatures up to 110°F (43°C) without noticeable damage. 
            However, the severity of the problem caused by high temperatures depends on the humidity level. 
            In order to successfully grow cotton plants, we must not have frequent rainfall during the ripening and harvest periods.
            
            Cotton will grow in almost any well-drained soil. 
            However, soils suitable for high yields are considered to be deep, well-drained sandy loams with sufficient clay, 
            organic matter, and moderate nitrogen and phosphorus concentrations. 
            The best yields tend to be achieved in calcium carbonate-rich loam soils. 
            A gentle slope is also sometimes required and generally aids in drainage.
            We started prepping the field after harvest in the fall with a good plow to a depth of about 14 inches (35 cm). 
            In this way we incorporate the remaining plants into the soil to improve the soil texture. 
            In late winter, we check for weeds and plow again to get our soil conditioned and ready for cotton seed.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "cotton.xml"/>
          <elseif cond="cotton == '4'" />
          <prompt>Cotton seeds are one of the most important parameters for a good yield. 
            Growers should only use certified seeds and avoid sowing seeds that have a shelf life of more than 2 years.
           We sow cotton seeds directly in the fields with special seeders. 
            These machines make small trenches for the seeds to a predetermined depth, place the seeds in them at a certain distance, 
            and then cover them lightly with soil. 
            In most cases, these machines also apply a predetermined amount of granular fertilizer between the seeds. 
            We add an average of 55 lbs of cotton seed and 440 lbs of fertilizer per hectare in the planter. 
            Sow seeds 1.5 – 2 inches deep. To facilitate mechanical harvesting, we leave an average of 3 feet between rows. 
            On the seeding line, when we sow, the seeds are spaced an average of 3 inches apart. 
            On average we have about 90,000-100,000 plants per hectare. 
            Therefore, the average number of cotton plants per acre is 40,000. 
            However, in some cases we can reach 70,000 cotton plants per acre, 
            but this can only be achieved by selecting specific varieties.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "cotton.xml"/>
          <elseif cond="cotton == '5'" />
          <prompt>
          As with any crop, there is no universal fertilization regimen, as every field is different and has different needs. 
            Ideally, an annual soil analysis is extremely important in diagnosing nutrient deficiencies 
            and taking corrective action under the direction of a licensed agronomist. 
            However, we will list the most common methods regarding fertilizing cotton plants.
            As a first rule of thumb, cotton plants consume double the amount of nitrogen compared to phosphorus and potassium. 
            Therefore, if soil analysis is not available, N-P-K 20-10-10 fertilizer is more appropriate. 
            A common fertilization schedule for many cotton growers is to 
            add 440 pounds of N-P-K 20-10-10 per hectare by drill during planting 
            and 440 pounds per hectare of N-P-K 20-10-10 during flowering (early summer). 
            Note that 1 hectare = 10,000 square meters = 2.47 acres.
            Another standard fertilization program is to add 550 pounds of ammonium nitrate, 
            400 pounds of N-P-K 0-46-0 and 400 pounds of N-P-K 0-0-50 per hectare throughout the year. 
            These amounts are usually divided evenly over 8 applications, 
            the first after planting, and the effects last about 6 weeks after flowering. 
            However, these are only common patterns and should not be followed without doing your own research and soil analysis.
            In other cases, farmers like to spray KNO3 on the leaves once a week after the first flowers appear. 
            Foliar spraying can provide fertilizers and pesticides at the same time, reducing labor costs.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "cotton.xml"/>
          <elseif cond="cotton == '6'" />
          <prompt>
          According to experience, from germination to cotton boll formation, cotton plants need at least 500 mm of water. 
            A large amount of U.S. cotton is grown on non-irrigated fields. 
            However, growing cotton commercially without providing an additional water supply is not an easy task. 
            The problem is not that the cotton plant needs water to thrive, 
            but because it needs water at a particular time during its development. 
            If you choose to rely entirely on rain, your cotton yields are at risk and may fluctuate from year to year.
            In areas where there is not enough rainfall in winter, farmers will irrigate fields with plenty of water before planting. 
            In most cases, farmers do not irrigate during the time between planting and flowering. 
            Once the plants bloom, cotton growers begin to water more frequently, every 5-7 days, depending on other parameters. 
            About 140 days after planting or 45 days after the bolls appear, 
            the bolls will begin to split naturally along the boll segment and begin to dry out. 
            Around the end of summer, many farmers stop irrigation or lightly irrigate every two weeks to help the cotton dry faster 
            and better. The most widely used system by professional farmers is drip irrigation.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "cotton.xml"/>
          <elseif cond="cotton == '7'" />
          <prompt>
          Cotton is usually ready for harvest 5 to 6 months after planting. 
            As with any crop, knowing exactly when to harvest takes years of experience. 
            Harvest with cotton harvester in autumn. 
            These machines, usually large tractors, strip the fibers from the plants and collect the bolls. 
            Immediately after harvest, the remaining cotton plants are destroyed with a shredder, and the fields are then plowed well.
            On average, we can harvest 4,400 to 8,800 pounds of cotton per hectare, or 1,760 to 3,527 pounds per acre. 
            What we harvest from the fields is called unmilled cotton and it is not traded.
            We have to hand the cotton over to the cotton gin, a machine that quickly 
            and easily separates the cotton fibers from their seeds and other objects. 
            It is estimated that 1 pound of unmilled cotton contains 32 to 33 percentage cotton fiber, 52 to 54 percentage cottonseed 
            and about 15% foreign matter such as stones, leaves, soil and so on. 
            However, these figures can be significantly skewed.
            Therefore, expected yields for ginned cotton range from 1,455 to 2,932 pounds per hectare, 
            or 589 to 1,187 pounds per acre. Note that these figures may vary significantly.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "cotton.xml"/>
          <elseif cond="cotton == '8'" />
          <prompt>
          Cotton plants are very sensitive to weeds, which actively compete with the plants for water, sunlight and valuable nutrients. 
            It is essential for all farmers to have a sound weed control strategy in place before starting to sow. 
            Necessary control measures may vary considerably in different countries, climate zones, legal frameworks, means of production and so on.
            Especially in the first 60 days after sowing, even very few weeds can negatively affect plant growth and ultimately fiber production.
            The first measures to control weeds are done during the first tillage before planting. 
            Then, depending on the texture of each field and the most common weeds in each area, 
            farmers typically spray with a variety of chemicals until the plants are well established. 
            A critical step in effective weed control is frequent tilling of the areas between plant rows. 
            This distance can vary from 2 to 4 feet, and farmers must be careful not to damage any part of the cotton plant 
            when doing the tillage. 
            Tilling the areas between planting rows will not only destroy any new growth of weeds, 
            but will also increase the aeration of the field. 
            In areas where contemporary broad-spectrum herbicides are not used, 
            farmers typically till once or twice a month during the vigorous growing period, with a final till after flowering.
            Many experienced farmers also sow wheat or barley immediately after harvesting cotton to reduce weeds.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "cotton.xml"/>
          <else />
          <prompt>Your choice is not valid.</prompt>
          <goto next="cotton.xml" />
        </if>
      </filled>
    </field>
  </form>
</vxml>
