<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<vxml version="2.1">
  <form>
    <field name="choose" type="digits">
      <prompt>
        Now you chan choose what you want to know further about rice.
        For general information about rice, press one.
	For Paddy and Soil Preparation, press two.
        For Rice planting, sowing requirements, press three.
	For Nutritional Management of Rice and Rice Fertilization, press four.
	For Rice Pests and Diseases, press five.
	For Rice Harvesting, Yield per Hectare and Storage, press six.
	If you want go back to action select, press zero.
      </prompt>
      <filled>
        <if cond="choose == '1'">
          <prompt>Rice is grown in 3 main ways:
	The first is grown in lowlands or rice fields. 
	Rice is grown on submerged land, either rain-fed or irrigated. 
	Water depths vary from 2 to 20 inches.
	The second is floating water rice and deep water rice. 
	Rice is grown on highly flooded land. 
	Water depths can exceed 20 inches to 200 inches (5 meters). 
	Only certain varieties of rice can be grown this way.
	The third is dryland rice cultivation, which is rarely done. 
	When rice is grown on land without water, 
	the crop is highly dependent on rain. 
	Natural rainfall is the only way to irrigate these fields. 
	In this case, we have to take into account that there should be periods of frequent rains of 3 to 4 months. 
	This is absolutely necessary, and only then will the plants develop properly.
	In general, water protects rice plants from extreme cold and heat. 
	Water also prevents weeds from growing.

</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
        <elseif cond="choose == '2'" />
          <prompt>Rice is a resilient plant that can grow in almost all types of soil. 
	It can grow in wet or dry land as long as it is well watered.
	It can grow in wet or dry land as long as it is well watered. 			
	However, since we expect good yields from the fields, the soil must be prepared.
	First of all, the paddy field must be free of weeds and useless substances.
	When grown in lowlands and drylands, less water is required. 
	We can consider the following steps to prepare a rice field.
	Step 1: Build the embankment. Dykes help fields retain moisture from rainfall. 
	We can build 19 x 12 inch dikes around the field. 
	Each channel is usually 1.1 to 1.9 inches high and ensures the field is supplied with moisture during the rainy season.
	Step Two: Till after the soil has been well watered.
	Step 3: Level the field. 
	In dry land preparation, we store very little water in the fields and use tools such as planks to level the land.
	Step 5: Weed Control. 
	A common way to prevent weeds from growing is to let them grow for at least two weeks.
	After weeds emerge, apply herbicides.</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
	<elseif cond="choose == '3'" />
          <prompt>Seeds germinate and hatch for 1-2 days before direct sowing. 
	We sow the seeds 6 to 10 inches apart. 
	We then let water fill our fields immediately or about 8 to 12 days after direct seeding is complete.
	Next step is transplant.
	Sow seeds in rows 2 to 4 inches apart. 
	Once we have finished seeding the beds, 
	fill the beds with water to a maximum depth of 2 inches. 
	The rice plants are kept in the nursery for 15 to 40 days. 
	Rice seedlings are usually ready to transplant when they are 8 to 12 inches tall. 
	We transplanted rice seedlings linearly into the field in an 8" by 8" scheme, 
	that is, 8 inches between plants in rows and 8 inches between each row).
</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
	<elseif cond="choose == '4'" />
          <prompt>
		  The first step in the nutritional management of rice is fertilization.
		  One of the most common problems in rice production is nitrogen deficiency. 
		  It usually occurs during a critical growth stage (panicle development) when the plant needs more nitrogen. 
		  We can recognize these nitrogen deficiency symptoms by a strong discoloration of the crop. 
		  Nitrogen deficiency can be managed through effective nitrogen fertilization, adequate plant spacing, 
		  and proper water management. 
		  It is also important to control weeds that compete with rice for nitrogen, 
		  and consultation with a local licensed agronomist is recommended.
		
		Sufficient nitrogen application helps rice grow rapidly and provides us with high-quality grains. 
		  However, if nitrogen is applied in excess of the rice's needs, 
		  the overuse of nitrogen can lead to vigorous growth that attracts large numbers of pests. 
		  Nitrogen excess can be identified by looking at the leaves. 
		  Because in most cases the leaf color is an unusual green. 
		  Additionally, plants may have elongated stems. 
		  Farmers can often prevent excess nitrogen by checking the nitrogen concentration in the soil 
		  and then applying enough nitrogen to meet the needs of rice.
		
		  Potassium is also very important for achieving high yield in rice. 
		  It aids in plant disease resistance, root growth, thickness, leaf durability, panicle initiation and development. 
		  Potassium deficiency has a great impact on crop growth. 
		  These potassium deficiencies can be identified by the following symptoms.
		  First, there are black spots on the older leaves. The plant is dark green with yellow to brown leaves.
		Second, the leaves on the lower part of the plant may tend to curve downward.
		Third, the leaves on the upper part of the plant are short and dark green in color.
		Fourth, there are spots of necrosis on the panicles.
		Fifth, unhealthy root conditions. The roots are black, decreasing in density and length.
		Sixth, the leaves wilt early.
		</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
	<elseif cond="choose == '5'" />
          <prompt>
		There are three main types of insect pests in rice.
		  The first are rice planthoppers and leafhoppers; rice planthoppers often attack rice stems. 
		  Leafhoppers, in contrast, attack the aerial parts of plants. Attacked plants develop a dark brown color, as if burned.
		  The second type is leaf-eating insects; that is, a large number of insects that come to the rice leaves to obtain food.
		  The third is an insect that attacks the grain. 
		  The rice bug, known as the rice bug, specializes in attacking immature plants and feeding on their grains.
		  
		  There are also many kinds of diseases.
		  The first is bacterial wilt; this disease is caused by the bacteria Xanthomonas. 
		  Often occurs in temperate and tropical climates with high humidity. 
		  The main lesions are yellowing of the leaves.
		  The second is bacterial streak; this disease is also caused by Xanthomonas. 
		  It can be found on unhealthy and injured plants in areas with high humidity. 
		  Bacterial streak is the cause of dry and discolored leaves. 
		  The third is brown spot; it is a fungal disease that mainly infects leaves and panicles. 
		  Large brown spots begin to spread on the leaves. 
		  It is one of the most destructive rice diseases and is often seen in fields with high humidity.
		  The best way to control these pests and diseases is prevention. 
		  Rice farmers can consider the following measures.
		  Between seasons, the fields and equipment used in the paddy fields must be properly cleaned. 
		  And use certified torrents. Avoid over fertilizing. 
		  In many cases, do not apply pesticides for 40 days after planting. 
		  Store grains properly. 
		  Try to keep the grain stored in containers with 13-14% humidity.
		</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
	<elseif cond="choose == '0'" />
          <prompt>Why is it so important to harvest on time?
		  The biological cycle of rice, that is, the number of days from emergence to harvest, varies from 95 days to nearly 250 days. 
		  Moderately mature varieties are ready to harvest 120 to 150 days after planting. 
		  When the kernels start to turn yellow and become hard, we can estimate when to harvest.
		  To be able to maximize the quality and yield of the grain, it is very important to harvest the rice crop on time. 
		  If we harvest too early, the collected grains will be immature, they will have poor milling resilience and will break easily. 
		  On the other hand, if the crop is harvested too late, grains can fall from the panicles, causing serious losses. 
		  Generally, harvesting begins only when the grains are 80-85% ripe or golden in color.
		  Harvesting can be done manually or mechanically. 
		  During manual harvesting, workers use sharp knives to collect rice stalks from the paddy field. 
		  They then carefully wash and separate the damaged rice plants. 
		  Mechanical harvesting can be done with a combination of machines for all operations such as cutting, threshing and cleaning.
		  
		  Drying is an important process to reduce the moisture content of grain. 
		  After harvest, grain typically contains about 25% moisture. 
		  If we let the grain grow after harvesting, it can cause discoloration and possible attack by pests. 
		  Therefore, before storing the grain, in most cases farmers dry the grain. There are two drying methods. 
		  Traditional and mechanical methods. 
		  In most cases, grain must be dried within 24 hours of harvest.
		  Due to its low and almost zero cost, traditional drying methods are preferred and adopted in many countries. 
		  We can dry the rice grains by exposing them to sunlight. 
		  Workers can spread the grains on carpet or sidewalks until they dry.
		  
		  In addition, mechanical drying can also be used. 
		  This method is based on removing moisture from the grain with heated air. 
		  This needs to be done with a different type of dryer.
		  The average yield of rice (seed) is 3-6 tons per hectare. 
		  In some countries, such as Australia and Egypt, yields can increase to a staggering 10-12 tons or more per hectare. 
		  Of course, such high yields can be achieved by experienced farmers after years of practice.
		  If you want go back to action select, press zero in next step.
		</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
        <else />
          <prompt>Your choice is not valid.</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
        </if>
      </filled>
    </field>
  </form>
</vxml>
