<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<vxml version="2.1">
  <form>
    <field name="sorghum" type="digits">
      <prompt>
      What information do you want to check?
      For general information, press one.
      For land preparation, press two.
      For seed treatment, press three.
      For sowing method, press four.
      For field management, press five.
      For pest control, press six.
      If you want to end this sorghum information, press zero.
      </prompt>
      <filled>
        <if cond="sorghum == '0'">
          <prompt> Now you can end this sorghum information.</prompt>
          <goto next= "goodbye.xml"/>
        <elseif cond="sorghum == '1'" />
          <prompt>Sorghum planting can be divided into spring cropping and autumn cropping, 
            which should be determined according to individual planting conditions and local climate conditions. 
            Usually the sowing period of spring crops is from the end of March to mid-April of the lunar calendar. 
            The time should not be too early, because the temperature of early sowing is low, the growth is slow, 
            and it is easy to die in cold currents. 
            For autumn crops, sowing should be done between the end of May and the end of June in the lunar calendar. 
            The time should not be too late, so as not to encounter low temperatures in the middle and late stages of growth, 
            which will affect growth and delay maturity.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "sorghum.xml"/>
          <elseif cond="sorghum == '2'" />
          <prompt>
            Sorghum has no strict requirements on the soil and can be planted in general plots, 
            but it should be avoided as far as possible in the plots of heavy stubble and stubble. 
            Due to the well-developed root system of sorghum, deep plowing should be carried out when planting sorghum. 
            When cultivating the land, it is best to control the depth of the cultivated land at 20-25 cm, 
            and at the same time combine the fertilization of the soil, which is conducive to the increase of sorghum planting yield.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "sorghum.xml"/>
        <elseif cond="sorghum == '3'" />
          <prompt>There are two kinds of sowing methods: on-demand and drill. 
            Generally, drill is the main method. 
            The seeds are evenly spread in the planting ditch and then covered with soil about 3 cm thick. 
            It is advisable to sow sorghum at a depth of 3 to 4.5 centermeters, and suppress it in time after sowing, 
            and use 20 kg per hectare with a general seed amount.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "sorghum.xml"/>
           <elseif cond="sorghum == '4'" />
          <prompt>
          Thinning and retaining seedlings.
            Thin the seedlings when the seedlings grow 3-4 leaves, and thin the seedlings with 5 to 6 leaves. 
            The principle of keeping seedlings is that large ears are easy to thin, and small ears are easy to dense. 
            Generally, when keeping seedlings, it is necessary to ensure that the density of seedlings is 105,000-120,000 plants per hm2.
            Intertillage weeding.
            During the growth period of sorghum, according to the occurrence of weeds, implement intertillage weeding 2 to 3 times, 
            especially in the early growth period, pay special attention to weed removal, so as not to affect the growth. 
            Water and fertilizer management.
            Sorghum is drought-tolerant, but in the period of young ear formation and milk maturity, 
            in case of drought, the yield will be greatly affected, and appropriate irrigation should be given. 
            In the rainy season, accumulated water should be removed at any time to avoid pests and diseases 
            and prolong the maturity period; fertilization must first be applied in time after the sorghum emerges. 
            Secondly, urea and agricultural fertilizers should be topdressed at the sorghum jointing stage, booting stage, and filling stage.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "sorghum.xml"/>
           <elseif cond="sorghum == '5'" />
          <prompt>
            The key points of pest control in sorghum high-yield planting technology are the control of white spot, smut, armyworm, and corn borer. 
            The focus is on prevention, and agronomic measures, physical measures, 
            chemical prevention and control measures can be used for targeted treatment.
          </prompt>
          <goto next= "sorghum.xml"/>
        <else />
          <prompt>Your choice is not valid.</prompt>
          <goto next="sorghum.xml" />
        </if>
      </filled>
    </field>
  </form>
</vxml>
