<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<vxml version="2.1">
  <form>
    <field name="choose" type="digits">
      <prompt>
        Now you chan choose what you want to know further about rice.
        For general information about rice, press one.
	For Paddy and Soil Preparation, press two.
        For Rice planting, sowing requirements, press three.
	For Nutritional Management of Rice and Rice Fertilization, press four.
	For Rice Pests and Diseases, press five.
	For Rice Harvesting, Yield per Hectare and Storage, press six.
	If you want go back to action select, press zero.
      </prompt>
      <filled>
        <if cond="choose == '1'">
          <prompt>Rice is grown in 3 main ways:
	The first is grown in lowlands or rice fields. 
	Rice is grown on submerged land, either rain-fed or irrigated. 
	Water depths vary from 2 to 20 inches.
	The second is floating water rice and deep water rice. 
	Rice is grown on highly flooded land. 
	Water depths can exceed 20 inches to 200 inches (5 meters). 
	Only certain varieties of rice can be grown this way.
	The third is dryland rice cultivation, which is rarely done. 
	When rice is grown on land without water, 
	the crop is highly dependent on rain. 
	Natural rainfall is the only way to irrigate these fields. 
	In this case, we have to take into account that there should be periods of frequent rains of 3 to 4 months. 
	This is absolutely necessary, and only then will the plants develop properly.
	In general, water protects rice plants from extreme cold and heat. 
	Water also prevents weeds from growing.

</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
        <elseif cond="choose == '2'" />
          <prompt>Rice is a resilient plant that can grow in almost all types of soil. 
	It can grow in wet or dry land as long as it is well watered.
	It can grow in wet or dry land as long as it is well watered. 			
	However, since we expect good yields from the fields, the soil must be prepared.
	First of all, the paddy field must be free of weeds and useless substances.
	When grown in lowlands and drylands, less water is required. 
	We can consider the following steps to prepare a rice field.
	Step 1: Build the embankment. Dykes help fields retain moisture from rainfall. 
	We can build 19 x 12 inch dikes around the field. 
	Each channel is usually 1.1 to 1.9 inches high and ensures the field is supplied with moisture during the rainy season.
	Step Two: Till after the soil has been well watered.
	Step 3: Level the field. 
	In dry land preparation, we store very little water in the fields and use tools such as planks to level the land.
	Step 5: Weed Control. 
	A common way to prevent weeds from growing is to let them grow for at least two weeks.
	After weeds emerge, apply herbicides.</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
	<elseif cond="choose == '3'" />
          <prompt>Seeds germinate and hatch for 1-2 days before direct sowing. 
	We sow the seeds 6 to 10 inches apart. 
	We then let water fill our fields immediately or about 8 to 12 days after direct seeding is complete.
	Next step is transplant.
	Sow seeds in rows 2 to 4 inches apart. 
	Once we have finished seeding the beds, 
	fill the beds with water to a maximum depth of 2 inches. 
	The rice plants are kept in the nursery for 15 to 40 days. 
	Rice seedlings are usually ready to transplant when they are 8 to 12 inches tall. 
	We transplanted rice seedlings linearly into the field in an 8" by 8" scheme, 
	that is, 8 inches between plants in rows and 8 inches between each row).
</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
	<elseif cond="choose == '4'" />
          <prompt>Ok. The service is in French now.</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
	<elseif cond="choose == '5'" />
          <prompt>Ok. The service is in French now.</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
	<elseif cond="choose == '0'" />
          <prompt>Ok. Now you can choose your action again.</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
        <else />
          <prompt>Your choice is not valid.</prompt>
          <goto next="rice.xml" />
        </if>
      </filled>
    </field>
  </form>
</vxml>
